<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Publications on marksprevak.com </title>
    <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) Mark Sprevak.</rights>
    <updated>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The computable universe</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/the-computable-universe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/the-computable-universe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The theory that the whole universe is a computer is a bold and striking one. It is a theory of &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;: the entire universe is to be understood, fundamentally, in terms of the universal computing machine that Alan Turing introduced in 1936. We distinguish between two versions of this grand-scale theory and explain what the universe would have to be like for one or both versions to be true. Spoiler: the question is in fact wide open – at the present stage of science nobody knows whether it’s true or false that the whole universe is a computer. But the issues are as fascinating as they are important, so it’s well worthwhile discussing them. We begin right at the beginning: what exactly &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a computer?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realism about cognitive science</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/realism-about-cognitive-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/realism-about-cognitive-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper starts from a simple puzzle. Realism about X is often glossed as the idea that Xs are &lt;em&gt;mind independent&lt;/em&gt;: Xs exist, and have their nature, independently of our beliefs, interests, attitudes, or other mental states. Xs are, in a sense ‘out there’, getting on with it independently of our mental life. If this is right, how should we understand realism about the mind? Mental processes and states are not mind independent: they don’t take place independently of our beliefs, interests, attitudes, or other mental states. Hence, it seems that we cannot be realists about them. Nevertheless, and in line with other areas of philosophy of science, there seems scope for asking the realist question about the posits of cognitive science, even if those posits make up our mental life. Should we be realists about the subpersonal mental representations or computations posited by cognitive science? Are these really ‘out there’, or are they only projections of the interests and attitudes of scientific theorisers? Unless we state realism differently from above, we have no way to even pose this question. In this paper, I explore the right way to state realism about cognitive science. I introduce different senses of mind-dependence and evaluate their merit to stating realism about cognitive science.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended cognition</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/extended-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/extended-cognition/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From intelligent machines to the human brain</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/from-intelligent-machines-to-the-human-brain-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/from-intelligent-machines-to-the-human-brain-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This chapter introduces the idea that computation is a key tool that can help us understand how the human brain works. Recent years have seen a revolution in the kinds of tasks computers can perform. Underlying these advances is the burgeoning field of machine learning, a branch of artificial intelligence, which aims at creating machines that can act without being programmed, learning from data and experience. Rather startlingly, it turns out that the same methods that allow us to make intelligent machines also appear to hold the key to explaining how our brains work. In this chapter, we explore this exciting new field and some of the questions that it raises.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is consciousness?</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/what-is-consciousness-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/what-is-consciousness-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Human consciousness is one of the greatest mysteries in the universe. From one point of view this should be surprising, since we know a great deal about consciousness from our own experience. One could say that our own conscious experience is the thing in the world that we know best. Descartes wanted to build the entirety of natural science on the foundation of our understanding of our conscious thought. Yet despite our intimate relationship with our own consciousness experience, from another point of view consciousness is a puzzling phenomenon. We have no idea what it is about us, as physical beings, that makes us conscious, why we have consciousness, or which creatures other than humans have consciousness. Not only is it hard to answer these questions, it is hard to know how to even start to find answers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts are containers</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/concepts-are-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/concepts-are-containers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machery (2009) argues that psychologists and philosophers mean different things by ‘concept’. Psychologists mean &lt;em&gt;bodies of knowledge used to categorise and infer&lt;/em&gt;; philosophers mean &lt;em&gt;constituent of propositional thought&lt;/em&gt;. Machery claims that generalisations about the former have no role to play in, and cast no light on, theories about the latter, and vice versa. We argue that, on the contrary, ‘concept’ has a single core meaning: &lt;em&gt;a container of stored knowledge pertaining to a single category&lt;/em&gt;. This meaning figures in the theorising of both psychologists and philosophers. The way ‘concept’ has been extended from this core matches how words for containers are often also used as shorthand for (a) what is contained by the container and (b) the label on a container. Our account explains what Machery’s two notions of ‘concept’ have in common, and how this single meaning is extended, patterned on similar cases of polysemy regarding containers, to apply to apparently different cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eliminativism and fictionalism</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/eliminativism-and-fictionalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/eliminativism-and-fictionalism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive coding</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/predictive-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/predictive-coding/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review of *The Language of Thought* by Susan Schneider</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/review-of-the-language-of-thought-by-susan-schneider/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/review-of-the-language-of-thought-by-susan-schneider/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Routledge Handbook of the Computational Mind</title>
      <link>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/routledge-handbook-of-the-computational-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Mark Sprevak</author>
      <guid>https://msprev.github.io/homepage-public/publications/routledge-handbook-of-the-computational-mind/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
